She is my only child,
我就这么一个独生女儿
Her mother passed away early.
她妈死得早
She has suffered a lot with me.
她跟我吃了不少苦
That's enough money for you to raise her.
那笔钱足够你把她抚养成人了
For the sake of 20 years of friendship, please.
看在二十年交情的份上拜托了
Don't worry, I'll treat her like my birth daughter.
你放心吧我会像对亲生女儿一样待她的
Xiao Ju.
小菊
Cut.
停
Director, is it good?
导演行吗
Good, cameraman, how do you think?
行摄影师你看怎么样
OK, good.
OK 这儿一条过
Every unit takes a look at this.
你们各部门再看看有什么问题没有
Has our lighting crew's work ever been poor?
灯爷的活儿什么时候差过
- Makeup has no problem. - Alright.
好了 服化道没问题
Good, it's done.
行行行过了
Director, the sound isn't good enough.
导演声音差点儿
What's wrong?
怎么回事
- Come on, girl, take a rest. - Yu Hong.
姑娘拍得不错喝瓶汽水歇会 于红
The stair sound is wrong,
这楼梯声不对
could you ask set decorator to enhance it?
能不能让置景再加工一下
More specific.
你说具体点
I suggest adding a layer of pallets
我的意思是不是增加一层托板
I suggest to improve the thickness of the floor.
提高楼板的厚度
- It's not easy. - The budget is only 700 thousands.
这事可够呛 就七十万
Where do you get that much money?
哪来那么多钱
Then you tell me.
那您说吧
Forget it. We won't record the scene at the same time.
那就算了吧这场戏不搞同期录音了
You guys find a place to do some motion effects.
你们找个地方做点动效
- Alright. - Yu Hong!
于红 好吧
_ Yu Hong! ' Yes?
哎
- Treats on you after shooting. - Okay, no problem.
姑娘 拍完戏请客啊 行啊没问题
- The ratio is one to three... - Only a bottle of soda.
一比三的片 一瓶汽水就打发我啊
Just change the script as I said.
你按我说的把这个剧本改过来
Don't forget to fill the film.
别忘了给胶卷啊
It's not working now. Listen to me.
现在这样不行听我的没错
Don't always show off yourself, okay?
别总展览你那点本事好不好
As if you really have some kind of supernatural power.
好像你真会什么特异功能似的
Go and make up some sound after the scene today.
今天拍完了戏跟着他去补点音
The ones we recorded just now don't work at all.
刚才录的那些根本不行
Huo Feng, finish the recording before you do anything else, take it easy.
霍峰补完录音再干旁的悠着点
Director, you try too hard, don't you?
导演 您戏过了吧
Take care. We'll go to your house for a wedding reception tomorrow.
您慢走赶明儿上您家我喝喜酒去
Bye bye, assholes.
又请走一家混蛋
Director Li.
林主任
The building is almost empty,
这楼可搬得差不多了
I'll help you whenever you need.
您什么时候搬到时候我给您帮忙
What director?
什么主任
I have no one or no car to help me, How can I move?
我现在是要人没人要车没车怎么搬
Talk to the head of your unit.
您跟您单位头儿说去呀
Before I retired, I got a raise in salary and a guarantee.
退下来之前又涨工资又下保证
But now? Damn it!
可现在哼他娘的
What about your son?
那您儿子呢
Forget it, he is ungrateful.
别提了儿子白养
He's been abroad for over a year, and he doesn't even send me a letter.
出国一年多了连封信都不来
Look at you, you are angrier than I am.
瞧您 , 您的气比我还大
I'll talk to the leader tomorrow.
要不 改明儿我上单位给您说说去
No one wants to live in this crappy building.
谁愿意住这个破楼啊
You Fei.
尤飞
Listen, hurry up!
我告诉你抓点儿紧
Wait.
你等等
Oh, it's you, Master Fang.
哎哟是您呐房爷
Why haven't you moved yet?
你怎么还不搬
I've urged you for hundreds of times.
我这已经催你第八百遍了
Yes, you have a good memory. What will I get?
是啊您好记性啊给几间
Didn't we agree? Two-bedroom apartment.
不是说好了吗两室一厅
We have made a deal too. Not moving without a three-bedroom apartment.
咱哥们也早说好了没三室一厅不搬
You live alone, this is already enough for you.
我说就你一个人住这就已经够照顾你的啦
Cut the crap, I won't move.
你少来这套我就是不搬
I won't chicken out.
要磕咱就磕
By tomorrow the building will be empty, it'll be all mine.
赶明儿这楼上都搬空了咱哥们一个人住
How about that?
怎么着
What kind of people live in this building?
这楼里住的都是些什么玩意儿
Thank you.
谢谢了啊
Huo Feng, I'm telling you.
霍峰我可告诉你
You're one of the three families who stuck in this building.
这楼里可就剩下你们三户了
What's wrong with you today? I'm disappointed about your attitude.
你今儿怎么了就您这态度我很遗憾
Disappointed?
哼遗憾
You won't feel that if you were mine.
咱俩换个位置你就不觉得遗憾了
Speak! When will you move?
说吧什么时候搬
After two weeks.
俩星期以后吧
I'm busy making a movie now, don't have time.
现在正忙着拍戏实在没时间
When the time comes, I'll help Lin move.
到时候 我帮老林一块搬
You film makers only know how to educate others.
你们这些拍电影的就知道教育别人
When it's your turn, it's not the same thing.
轮到自己就不是那么回事了
Old Li, it's not appropriate to talk like this, right?
哎老李这么说话不合适吧
If you don't move in two weeks,
如果两个星期之后还不搬
it's not just inappropriate talking.
就不光是话合适不合适了
People like you deserve some tough measures.
对你们这种人不采取点措施就不行
What an asshole, let's go.
真是的走吧
What's wrong? Start again.
怎么搞的重来
Footsteps, take two.
脚步声第二次
Ready,acHon.
预备 开始
Why do you keep wandering off?
我说你怎么老走神啊
I feel like someone's staring at me.
我总觉着有人在盯着我
Yes, I'm staring at you.
没错我在盯着你
No, it's a big pair of eyes.
不是一双特大的眼睛
Silly you.
你这个人呐
Come on, don't be paranoid.
行了别疑神疑鬼的
If we don't finish this, you're gonna have to stay here.
再录不完你恐怕得住这儿了
It's nice, though.
不过 这倒不错
In your dream.
做梦
Forget about the dream, let's record again.
别管做不做梦再来一遍
Footsteps, take three.
脚步声第三次
Ready, set
预备 开始
Yes, I saw it.
没错 我看见了
A little girl staring at me.
是个小女孩在盯着我
She is in the basement.
她在地下室里
I think you are crazy today.
我看你今天有点神经
Forget it. The first two recordings are enough.
算了前面录的反复用两次够了
Look, I forget to turn off the machine when you scream.
你瞧你一乱叫机器都忘了关
Listen.
你听
Damn it, what's wrong?
见鬼怎么回事
Don't go there.
哎别去
It's okay, stay there.
没事你等着
Yu Hong, Yu Hong, Yu Hong.
于红
Damn you, who are you scaring?
你大爷的你吓唬谁呢你
- Did you go down to the basement. - What?
你下地下室了 怎么啦
You've got a lot of guts. It's been locked up for over 10 years.
你丫胆够大的呀十几年了一直锁着
Who opened it?
谁开的
I don't know. I was recording,
我哪知道刚才我在录音
then I heard something so I went down to check it out.
听里边有动静就下去看了看
Huo Feng, you haven't been here long enough to know,
哎哟 霍峰你搬来时间不长不知道
several people have committed suicide in this basement.
这地下室里自杀了好几口子人
No one dares to go down after that.
后来可就没人敢进去了
What's going on? Start again.
怎么搞的重来
Footsteps, take two.
脚步声第二次
Ready, set
预备 开始
Why do you keep wandering off?
我说你怎么老走神啊
I feel like someone's staring at me.
我总觉着有人在盯着我
Yeah, I'm staring at you.
没错我在盯着你
No, it's a big pair of eyes.
不是一双特大的眼睛
Silly You.
你这个人呐
Come on, don't be paranoid.
行了别老疑神疑鬼的
If we don't finish this, you're gonna have to live here.
再录不完 恐怕你得住这儿了
It's nice, though.
不过 这倒不错
In your dream.
做梦
Forget about the dream. Let's record again.
别管做不做梦再来一遍
Ready, set
预备 开始
Yes, I saw it.
没错 我看见了
A little girl staring at me. She's in the basement.
是个小女孩在盯着我她在地下室里
Hello?
喂
Hello? Why is your phone always busy?
喂你的电话怎么老占线
I haven't used the phone.
我一直没用电话
Nonsense.
哼 瞎说
Why do you always lie?
哎你怎么老说谎
You won't believe me anyway.
我解释你也不信
Why didn't I see you when I came out?
哎我一出来怎么看不见你了
After you went in, I called you a few times but you didn't answer.
你进去以后我叫了你几声你没答应
I... I felt a little...
我我感觉到有点
What? What do you feel?
什么你感觉什么
Did you find anything inside?
你进去发现什么了
No, but I recorded a very strange sound.
没有可我录到了非常奇怪的声音
When you went in, I felt a man take a little girl...
你进去后我觉得有一个男人把一个小女孩
Could you come over right away?
你是不是马上来一趟
Yes, I'll be right there.
好的我马上去
Who is it?
谁
Wait a minute.
你等一下啊
What is it, director?
什么事导演
What's wrong with you?
你这是怎么啦
Nothing.
没什么
I just found a strange thing.
只不过发现一件怪事
Yes?
哦
Maybe I do have special powers.
也许我真的有特异功能
You're probably too tired these days.
这几天你可能太累了
Let's go dance and relax.
咱们去跳个舞轻松一下
Okay, I'll go change.
好我去换衣服
I'll wait for you.
那我等着你啊
The director wants to see me. I will meet you later. Bye.
导演找我有事我得晚点去再见
I saw a little girl in the basement.
我看见一个小女孩在地下室里
But the door was sealed. It was weird.
可门是被封着的真怪
Do you think I'm hallucinating or seeing a ghost,
您说我是幻觉呢还是见了鬼
or is it supernatural?
是特异功能
You can choose to believe in supernatural powers or not.
特异功能不可信又不能不信
Huo Feng is so brave. He went into the basement by himself.
霍峰的胆真大他一个人进了地下室了
The basement?
地下室
I'm here.
哎 我在这儿呢
Wait for me.
你等我一下啊
This way.
到这边
Have you decided?
你想好了吗
Sure.
当然了
Name a price.
开个价吧
Two thousand. Name a place.
两千你说个地方吧
Tuan Cheng.
团城
All right, tomorrow at 5 p.m.
好吧明天下午五点钟
Tomorrow at '5 pm.
嗯 明儿下午五点
- That's right. - I'll see you there.
对 不见不散
Alright.
好吧
What are you doing here, young man?
小伙子在这儿干吗
You're really strong, you scared me.
您老人家手劲真不小吓了我一跳
You movie maker are crazy. Looking for inspiration here.
你们这搞电影的就爱犯神经 在这找灵感
I want to record some sound effects when no one's around.
我想趁没人的时候录点声音效果
I don't know your business.
我不懂你们这行
But why are you recording when there is no sound?
可我明白 这没声你录什么
That's true,
那倒是
but I always thought there was something wrong with this building.
不过我总觉得这楼有点毛病
That's right. I couldn't open the bathroom door
没错我那浴室的门呐
this afternoon.
今天下午一撞上就怎么也打不开
The TV was also out of order.
电视也跟着出毛病
Come on, let's take a look.
来给我瞧瞧去啊
Sure.
行啊
Nothing's wrong with it.
没毛病啊
This is really strange.
这可真怪了
How come when I turn it on, the picture doesn't come out?
怎么我一开就是不出影呢
Have one.
来一根
Come on, take a look at the lock.
来再给我看看那把锁
See?
你看
Maybe the rotor is broken. You are moving anyway.
可能撞锁坏了也住不了几天了
I'll help you move later.
过两天我帮您搬家
Let's use the toilet across the hall for the next two days.
这两天先用对门的厕所吧
Don't mention moving. Even if you can help me move,
别提搬家了就算你能帮我搬
I have no energy to do the cleaning in the future.
将来打扫收拾什么的我也力不从心呐
Besides, the new building is low and suffocating.
再说新楼都矮憋得慌
It's fine now, isn't it?
现在不是挺好吗
You're very attached to this building.
您对这楼蛮有感情啊
Of course, I've lived here for decades.
可不住了几十年了嘛
You've been living in this room?
一直住这屋
I used to live in the basement.
以前住地下室
The basement? I heard that a few people committed suicide there.
地下室 听说那儿自杀过几个人
It was a little girl named Xiao Ju.
是个小姑娘叫小菊的
She was only 14 years old when she committed suicide.
才十四岁就自杀了
Why would such a young girl wants to commit suicide?
那么小的姑娘干吗要自杀
We'll have to ask the king of hell.
那得去问阎王爷去了
What about her parents?
她父母呢
Her mother committed suicide by jumping off a building.
她妈是跳楼自杀的
For what?
为了什么
How would I know? You don't have much options in those days.
叫我问谁去啊那年月活不了只有死
You were in charge at that time? You must have known the truth.
那时候您是头头肯定知道内情
Charge for what?
头头又怎么样
Those were the days of class struggle.
那是讲阶级斗争的年月
It was difficult when I was just promoted
我刚被结合上革委会副主任才难呢
About this room, it was...
就说这房吧当时把它
As soon as I came back, both father and daughter were dead.
我从外地一回来他们父女俩就都死了
Please come in.
请进
Who are you talking to?
您跟谁说话
Someone knocked on the door.
有人敲门
Why didn't I hear it?
我怎么没听见
Oh, I misheard.
嘿 我听错了
We all make mistakes sometimes.
谁都有错的时候
Listen.
你听
I thought it was you!
我当是谁呢原来是你呀
- Since you are here. - Let me introduce you to each other.
我来介绍一下
This is actress Yu Hong.
这是我们女主角于红
- This is Old Lin. - How are you?
这是老林 您好
You are commonly seen in movies.
常见常见在电影上
Let's sit inside.
屋里坐 屋里坐吧
Go inside.
进去吧
I've been watching your movies a lot.
我可常看你的电影啊
It's as simple as that.
就这么简单
Sounds simple. We're talking about the old days.
听着简单呐我们说以前的事了
It's okay, you guys keep talking.
没关系你们接着聊
After Old Li was in jail
老李进了监狱以后
it's been a hard time for her wife and daughter.
她们母女的日子实在不好过
A lot of people came after them.
很多人找她们麻烦
Her mother came to beg me.
她妈来求过我
She asked me to save Old Li and them
说是看在几十年同事的份上
that for the sake of colleagues for decades.
叫我救救老李和她们母女
But I was also in a hard time...
可是我也难呐那个时候
She was fine when her mother passed away.
她妈走的时候还好好的
I never thought she would not be able to survive.
万没想到她到底没挺住
The country was crazy, not to mention people.
国家都疯了何况人
Yu Hong, Yu Hong.
于红
Huo Feng! Huo Feng, help!
啊霍峰霍峰救救我
Why is there a problem again?
怪事怎么又出毛病了
Who?
谁
Huo Feng, Huo Feng, help me!
啊 霍峰 救救我
Huo Feng, help!
救命啊
Old Lin, Old Lin.
老林
Where are you?
你在哪儿
What the hell are you doing?
哎哎哎你大爷的你干吗呢你
Did you hear Lao Lin cry for help? He seems to have been beaten up.
你听见没有老林喊救命好像被人打了
I think you deserve a beating.
我看你小子就欠打
Go!
走
The dark doorway always attracts my attention.
那黑洞洞的门口总吸引着我的视线
- I saw it. - What?
我眼前就出现了 出现什么了
A man hanged a little girl.
一个男人吊死了一个小女孩
I saw him raping her in Old Lin's home.
在老林家我看见我看见他强奸
Wait, did you see it clearly?
等等你看出来的清楚吗
Yes, I was really scared.
清楚我当时真是怕极了
Do you think it's possible?
你说这事有可能吗
Firstly you confused me, and then you left without saying goodbye.
先是你把我闹糊涂了两次你都不辞而别
But the strangest thing to me was the process of Lin's death.
不过让我最奇怪的是老林死的过程
I recorded it a few hours before he died.
在他死前几小时我就录到了
That's it...
这是
a bad omen.
凶兆
What else did you feel?
你又感觉到什么了
Revenge.
报复
- Revenge? - Yes.
嗯
Who?
谁
A wronged spirit, the one born from the murder.
一个冤魂 因为谋杀生出的那个冤魂
Was it Xiao Ju? Are you saying that Old Lin killed her?
是小菊吗你说当初能是老林杀了她吗
Huo Feng, I really don't want to mention this now, I am scared.
霍峰我现在真的不想提这事了我有些怕
It's fine, I got you.
没什么有我呢
You should move out of the building quickly.
你赶快从楼里搬出来吧
I want to get to the bottom of this weird thing.
我想把这怪事弄清楚
Even if it's true, it's been more than ten years.
我看就算是真的也十几年了
Besides, Old Lin is already dead.
再说老林不是已经死了吗
I always think something else is going to happen.
我总觉得还要出事
There seems to be a force that attracts me to find out what's going on.
似乎有股力量吸引着我看个究竟再搬
You're right on time, well done.
我说你可真够准时的啊够意思
I'm serious. Take a look.
哥们也不含糊你看看
Here you go.
给你
This is real.
这可是真货
How is it?
怎么样
Rolled gold of Ming Dynasty.
大明包金
Two thousands, take a count.
两千块你点点吧
You count, I'll watch it.
还是您点 我看着
Two thousands in total.
整两千
I'll bring you the lotus bowl from the Song Dynasty tomorrow.
明几个我给你拿个宋代的莲花碗来
- I'll take all the real ones. - Okay.
真货我全要 好嘞
I don't want the broken ones.
伤的我可不要啊
Don't worry, it'll be fine.
放心吧错不了
Action!
开始
Go, keep going, keep going. Right, go.
走跟着走跟着走对对走
Looking for something, yes. Go, go, go.
找东西 对走啊走
Cut.
停
How is it?
怎么样
Look.
看
What did you say?
你说什么
The act is too bad. You go and talk to her.
这戏也太差了你再去给她讲讲
Come... put it on.
来先把衣服披上
Do you know what you are looking for?
知道让你找什么吗
This is a precious key your father left behind for you,
那是你父亲给你遗留下来一个珍贵的钥匙坠
This is a relic.
那是遗物
Not to pick up purses.
不是让你到处捡钱包
Fix her makeup, I said fix her makeup.
快去修修妆我说给她修修妆
I said let's do the next shot, right?
我说 咱们下个镜头的镜位对吧
Producer?
制片
Where is Huo Feng?
霍峰呢
He is not here.
霍峰不在
Go find him.
快去找
I want to ask about something.
我想打听一件事
How did the girl named Xiao Ju
十几年前十三号楼地下室
in the basement of Building 13 die?
那个叫小菊的女孩是怎么死的
Why are you asking about her after all this time?
都过这么久了你问她干什么
I want to write a movie script about the Cultural Revolution.
我想写个电影剧本是反映文化大革命的
I was there at that time.
当时是我出的现场
How can I put it?
怎么说呢
From the scene, it doesn't appear to be a case of murder.
从现场看不出一点他杀的痕迹
But the key around the victim's neck was hanging out of the rope.
可死者脖子上的钥匙却挂在绳外
There were suicides every day in those days.
那年头自杀的人天天都有
Why didn't you investigate at that time?
当时为什么不调查
The Police the procuratorate and the law department
那日子口公检法都砸烂了谁管
We just want to close the case.
能结案就了了
Be careful and quickly load the car.
大伙注意了啊赶快装车啊
Finish this scene and go back for dinner.
这个镜头拍完了回去吃饭
Director, Huo Feng is not here, people say he went out for business.
导演霍峰不在说有事出去了
Damn, if this scene can't use actual recording. Let's go back.
妈的 这场戏要不能同期我就不拍了撤
- Let's go. - Be careful..
噢撤喽 小心点
Please go.
小王快开车呀
Is that golden Buddha wanted by the upper class?
那金佛是上面要吗
Right. They asked for this.
没错当年是上面点名要他们家的金佛
You really don't know how the girl died?
你真不知道那姑娘是怎么死的吗
If I really knew the truth,
就他妈我这嘴知道
how could I not to tell you?
知道他能不说吗
This way.
这边走
- Dad. - Cut.
爸爸 停
This is not good.
哎这可不行
As the adopted daughter of this family,
作为这个家庭的养女
you don't want to accept your foster
你并不准备接受你养父的钱
father's money and the opportunity to go abroad.
和这次出国的机会
In order for your foster father's biological daughter to go abroad,
为了让你养父的亲生女儿出国
Tonight you are going to leave the house quietly
今天晚上你准备悄悄地离开这个家
and not to let your foster father know.
而且呢还不能让你的养父知道
You should not act from your look nor the body.
这时候你的表演不在表情上也不在形体上
It's all about...
而是在
---Your eyes.
要通过眼睛
You need to express the complex emotion
要从眼睛里看出你对你养父的
in your eyes to your foster father.
惜别之情和复杂的心态
Director, I'm afraid I can't do it.
导演 我怕出不来
- Roll back. - Alright.
大撤 好的
Yu Hong, you're going to be a super star in China.
于红你现在将要成为中国的大明星了
I have one more thing to tell you.
我还要告诉你一件事
This film will be shown on the international film festival.
这部影片将参加国际电影节
You may become an international star.
你可能成为国际明星
You know I never asked for anything from you.
你知道我对你从无所求
- How do you feel right now? - I...
你现在的心情是什么 我
Don't use words, just look into my eyes.
不要用语言而是看着我的眼睛
Look at me. Action!
看着 看着开机
Yu Hong. Yu Hong.
于红
- What's wrong with you? - What's wrong with her?
她怎么了 你这是怎么啦
My head is dizzy.
我的头晕极了
You did a good job just now.
你刚才这段戏演得不错嘛
Quick, take a rest over here.
快快快到这边休息一下
Sir, please take a rest, too.
老爷子你也先到后边休息一下
Please rest for a while.
您先歇会儿吧
Please sit here. Right, take a break.
来来来坐在这儿对休息一下
- Makeup! Costume! - Director! Director!
化妆服装 导演导演
- I have something to tell you. - What?
我想跟您说点事 什么事
The actor who played Ah'Si is sick, what should we do?
演阿四的演员病了您看怎么办呢
Find another actor.
再找一个吧
- We won't make it in time by tomorrow. - Yu Hong.
明天就要拍戏来不及啊 于红
- I don't care what happens to you. - What's wrong?
这是你的事我管不着 你怎么啦
- That feeling comes back. - What feeling?
那种感觉又出现了 什么感觉
Go over there.
走到那边去
Are you okay without Huo Feng?
哎霍峰不在你行吗
No problem, you can sit here
没问题您坐这儿吧
- Buddy, the price of TV has gone up again. - I know.
哥们： 彩电又涨价了 这事我知道
Listen to me, hurry up and ask someone for an entitlement.
我跟你说赶紧着托个人找个指标
Who? You?
谁换你给我换
Just that vendor...
我告诉你就街上那摊贩
That feeling came back when I looked into his eyes.
我看着他眼睛的时候那种感觉又出现了
He was the one who hanged a little girl.
是他把一个小女孩给吊死了
That person, how I feel a bit like the director.
那个人我怎么觉得那个人有点像导演
- You mean Zheng Lei? - A bit similar.
你是说郑磊 好像有点像
Director, listen to me, this is too difficult.
导演您听我说这也太难点儿了
I don't care if it's difficult or not.
难不难的你跟我说不着
As long as we don't use location recording, you won't show up.
只要不同期录音你就不照面了啊
A man died in our building.
我们楼里死了个人
What does this have to do with you?
这跟你有什么关系
- I found him. - You didn't kill him, did you?
人是我发现的 人不是你杀的吧
How is that possible?
这怎么可能
I know you're not that smart.
我知道你还没有精明到这个程度
So I can't be a director.
所以我还当不了导演
I think so. You'll probably never be a director.
是啊我看也是你大概永远也当不了导演
Director, please give me one more day.
哎导演您再多给一天时间吧
It's hard to find an actor like Ah'Si.
像阿四这样的演员可真是不好找
You need to overcome the difficulty.
要克服困难嘛
- Director... - let me introduce one guy to you.
哎导演 我给你们介绍一个吧
How about the one lives in our building?
我们楼里的怎么样
- Suitable? - Perfectly suitable.
合适吗 再合适不过了
How's the acting?
戏怎么样
Well, everyone is acting in life.
戏嘛生活中谁都在演
I think you can be a real director.
我看你真可以当导演了
- Let me see his picture first. - Okay.
这样吧先拿个照片来让我看看 好吧
What did you feel after staring at the director for so long?
你刚才盯了导演半天又感觉到什么了
Nothing.
什么也没有
I think the director is not that kind of person.
我觉得导演他不是那种人
- Not a chance. - Not a chance?
不可能
Go back to that place and feel it again. I'll record it again.
走到老地方去你再感觉一下我再录一次
How about it?
怎么样
No, I can't feel it.
不行感觉不清
Go inside and listen to see if we get anything.
到屋里听听看看录到什么没有
You just said you felt a person.
哎你刚才说你感觉到一个什么人
Yu Hong.
于红
What did you say?
啊你说什么
It seems that there is a person holding a shiny object.
哦好像有个人手里拿个发亮的东西
A shiny object?
发亮的东西
- Is this Huo Feng? - Hello?
霍峰吗 喂
- It's Directer. - Let me.
是导演 我来
Hello, it's me.
喂是我
It takes so long to fetch a picture.
一个照片拿这么长时间啊
And the lead actress left with you.
还把女主角给拐跑了
Director Zheng, I'll meet You Fei if he's back.
郑导尤飞不在我等会儿见他
I've sent a car to pick you up.
我已经派车去接你们了
I've just watched the demo. Yu Hong has some shots to retake.
刚看完样片于红有几个镜头要补
You guys come back to the studio right away.
你们马上回厂里来
Is the director...
导演是不是
asking us to go back immediately.
让咱们马上回厂
You have to retake some scene, the car will arrive immediately
你得补戏车马上到
I think it should retake too.
哼我觉着也该补
Huo Feng, Huo Feng!
霍峰霍峰
Someone's calling you downstairs.
哎楼下有人叫你
- What? - Huo Feng.
什么 霍峰
Damn, I misheard.
妈的 我听岔了
Hey! The director asked me to pick you up.
哎导演让我来接你们
Don't forget to bring the photo with you. Come down quickly.
哦别忘了把照片带上快下来吧
Okay, we'll be right there.
好的 马上就下来啊
Right, I'll go check on You Fei, you go down first.
对了我去看看尤飞你先下去吧
Okay, hurry up!
好你快点啊
Photo? I don't have photo.
照片 我没照片啊
I have one on my ID card, I'll find it for you.
我身份证有一张我给你找找啊
Hurry UP!
快点儿啊
Where is it?
放哪儿了我是
My poor memory.
瞧我这记性
- You mean this one? - Which one?
你说的是这张 哪张
This one.
这张
I don't remember I have this photo.
哟我不记得有这么张照片啊
That's a nice Buddha statue. Where did you get it?
这佛像不错哪儿来的
Someone asked me to sell this.
哦这玩意儿是人家托我卖的
But he died a few days later.
可是没过几天那人就死了
It's not that simple. There's a story.
没这么简单吧这里面有故事
Don't be ridiculous. Ever since I got this, I've been rich.
别逗了自从有了这宝贝哥们就发了
Maybe you take it from the one in basement.
没准是你黑地下室那家的吧
No. Believe it or not. Dead men tell no tales.
哪儿啊信不信由你这叫死无对证
Huo Feng, hurry UP!
霍峰 你快点
Director, the photo.
导演 照片
Is that him? Where does he live?
是他 这人住哪儿
He's our neighbor.
我们邻居呀
That son of a bitch, bring him to me.
这个王八蛋把他给我找来
What's wrong?
您怎么啦
It's him. Go.
定他了去呀
Great Buddha, thanks to you, I got rich.
老佛爷爷托您的福您让我发了财
And now, please make me famous.
今儿个再托您的福您让我成名怎么样
- You Fei. - Coming!
尤飞 噢来啦
You Fei. You're going to act.
尤飞定你演戏啦
I'm coming!
来啦来啦
Huo Feng.
霍峰
You Fei.
尤飞
Weird.
嘿邪了嘿
You Fei, hurry up!
尤飞快来呀
Huo Feng, where are you?
霍峰你在哪儿呢
I'm here.
在这儿呢
- Huo Feng! Huo Feng! - You Fei, hurry up.
霍峰 尤飞快来呀
Liu, Take me home.
刘儿送我回家
Huo Feng! Huo Feng!
霍峰
Help!
救命啊
Bastard!
王八蛋
Director, I'm all set here.
导演我这可全准备好了啊
Ready... Start!
哦预备开始
Lower... lower...
降降降
Steady.
稳一点
Lower... slowly...
降慢
Good”.
好好
We've been already out of the picture, why not stop?
都出画半天了停不停机呀
Cut.
停
This is too dull, maybe there can be some new ideas.
这也太深沉了没准还能出点新意
You Fei, You Fei.
尤飞尤飞
What's wrong?
怎么回事
Sorry, Director.
导演 对不起啊
Guys, take a break. Where's Huo Feng?
你们大伙先休息霍峰呢
Didn't you just tell him to find the actor?
您刚才不是让他找那个演员去了吗
Send me a car quickly!
赶快给我派车
Huo Feng! Huo Feng!
霍峰霍峰
Why are you standing there?
你站在那儿干吗呢
Director, come on, come here!
导演 来呀 过来呀
Xiao Ju, you can't revenge like this!
啊 小菊你不能这样报复
Director? It's his turn.
导演 该轮到他了
- Hello? - Is this Huo Feng?
喂 是霍峰吗
- Yu Hong, I've got it again. - What did you say?
于红 我又录到了 你说什么
I see. What you feel is the past.
我明白了你感觉到的是过去
What I record is the future.
我录到的是未来
What's going to happen again?
那又要发生什么事
I'm telling you, it's the director.
告诉你下一个该轮到导演了
What should we do? He's already on the way to your place.
那怎么办他已经坐车去你那儿了
No, I can't let him die like this.
不不能让他就这么死了
I want to get the proof that he killed Xiao Ju.
我要拿到他害死小菊的证据
Yes, you have to stop him. We can't let him die.
对你一定要阻止他千万不能让他死
This film is not done yet. It's very important to me.
这部影片还没完它对我很重要
Come on, listen to my recording and feel the past again.
你赶快来听听我的录音再感觉一下过去
Okay-
好
Xiao Ju, I know you suffered injustice and horrible death.
小菊我知道你死得很冤也很惨
You hated the people who killed your parents.
你恨那些坑害你父母的人
And you hate the person who killed you.
更恨那个杀死你的人
Now you can finally take revenge in your own way.
你现在终于能用自己的方式复仇了
Maybe you think we living people are hideous.
也许你认为我们活着的人都很丑恶
But we humans have our own rules.
但我们人类也有自己的方式
The guilty will be punished.
有罪的人是要受到惩罚的
But definitely not your way.
可决不是你这种方式
Don't you go on like this.
你不要再这样继续下去了
I know, Zheng Lei is the criminal.
我知道郑磊就是罪犯
But I don't have evidence,
可我没有证据没有证据
You have to help me find evidence,
你要帮我找到证据
and let the law sanction him.
让法律制裁他
If you have anything to say, say it to the recorder.
有什么话就对着它讲吧
Go ahead.
讲吧
You Fei.
尤飞
Who are you?
你是谁
I already gave it back to you, Xiao Ju.
我还你了 还你了小菊
- You Fei. - I gave it back to you.
尤飞 我还你了
I already gave it back to you, Xiao Ju.
还你了小菊
Huo Feng.
霍峰
You Fei, you son of a bitch!
尤飞你这个王八蛋
Where's the stuff?
东西呢东西呢
I gave it back to you. Xiao Ju, I gave it back to you.
我还你了我还你了小菊还你了
You Fei, where's the golden Buddha?
尤飞 金佛在哪儿
Director Zheng.
郑导
He's gone crazy.
他疯了
- Crazy? - You've been here before, right?
疯了 你以前来过这楼吧
- Are you kidding? Take me to You Fei. - Stop!
你开什么玩笑走带我去找尤飞 站住
Go! If you don't leave, Xiao Ju will come to get you.
你快走你不走的话小菊她会来报复你的
I'll go back to the studio first. You should come, too.
我我先回棚里你马上也来
Drive! Get back!
快开车 回去
Find the evidence.
找到证据
Xiao Ju, you can't do this.
小菊 你不能这样
What do you want to say?
有什么话你说吧
HUO Feng!
霍峰
I'm in the house.
我在屋里
Huo Feng! Huo Feng! What's wrong?
霍峰霍峰你怎么啦
HUO Feng!
霍峰
I...
我
Huo Feng! Huo Feng!
霍峰霍峰
Hello? First aid station. Yes, I need first aid station. Yes.
喂要急救站对我要急救站急救站对
Is this First aid station?
喂急救站吗
I'm in room 208 of the No.13 eastern district.
对我是东区十三号208室
Please, come quickly!
对快来人呐快
Help! Help!
救命啊救命啊
Comrade Huo Feng is not in danger.
霍峰同志是因为录音机漏电
His brain was shocked by the tape recorder.
电击了他的脑神经没有生命危险
But it's hard to tell if he'll recover his mind.
但神志能否恢复很难讲啊
So he'll never be able to speak?
那他永远不能讲话吗
Didn't I tell you? It's hard to say.
我不是说了嘛很难讲啊
What about Yu Hong?
那于红怎么样
Yu Hong was mentally shocked.
于红她受了点惊吓神经上受了点刺激
We were about to transfer her to the hospital for treatment.
我们正准备让她转院治疗
Fortunately, she finished filming her scene.
幸亏她的戏拍完了
Tell us what happened.
你说说是怎么回事啊
Doctor, here's the story.
大夫事情是这样的
He found her by accident.
他是无意中发现她的
I also saw someone had harmed her in the past.
我当时也看见以前有人害她
She wanted to take revenge on those who hurt her.
她要去报复那些害她的人
He went to stop her and she ended up hurting him instead.
他去阻止她结果她反而害了他
Okay, okay, I understand. You should go home and get some rest.
好了好了我全明白了你回去好好休息吧
Doctor, I'm well now. I want to see him.
大夫我已经好了我要去看他
- Just leave. - I want to see him.
走吧走吧 我要去看他
The diagnosis is confirmed.
可以确诊了
It's a classic passive-aggressive personality disorder.
是典型的被动内攻击型人格异常
I'm not sick, I'm going to see him.
我没病 我要去看他
I'm not sick, doctor. I'm fine. I'm going to see him.
我没病大夫我已经好了我要去看他
Doctor, I'm not sick. I'm not sick.
大夫 我没病我没有病
Huo Feng, are you feeling better?
霍峰 好点儿吗
You know what, the director won an award. But we end up like this.
你知道吗- 导演获奖了可我们却这样了
I told them there was a ghost, but they said I was crazy.
我对他们说有鬼他们却说我疯了
Then I told them nothing happened,
后来我就对他们说什么也没发生过
I only remember that your ears were bleeding.
我只记得你两个耳朵在流血
I don't remember anything else.
其他的什么都忘了
And they said I was recovered.
他们呢反倒说我好了
I'm going to find that little ghost.
我要去找那个小冤魂
That's not fair to you.
这样对你太不公平了
- You... - What?
你 什么
You should go and help her.
你去找她去帮助她
She's right. Go to her.
她是对的去找她
Go and find her...
你去
This film...
本片
It's meant to evoke people's conscience.
意在唤起人们的良知
It's about raising people's conscience.
唤起人们在相处时的真诚
It seems that this film has achieved
看来这部影片已经达到了
to promote the virtues of our ancient people
促进我们古老民族的
including sincerity, kindness, mutual help, and the virtue of solidarity.
真诚善良互助团结的美德
Xiao Ju, Huo Feng asked me to take you to Zheng Lei.
小菊 霍峰让我带你去找郑磊
You can take revenge in your own way.
你可以用自己的方式进行报复
We'll help you get justice.
我们帮你讨个公道
But what's next?
可以后呢
I hope it will flourish.
我希望它能够发扬光大
I will feel greatly grateful for this.
为此我将感到无限的欣慰
Thank you!
谢谢大家谢谢
Director Zheng, what is your motive for making this film?
郑导演您拍这部片的动机是什么呢
This question... how to say...
你这个问题问得怎么说呢
It's a very complicated question.
这是一个很复杂的问题
I can't answer this right now, so please forgive me.
我一时很难回答你请你原谅好吗
Director Zheng, what is your opinion on domestic commercial films?
郑导演您对国内商业片有什么看法
Domestic commercial films...
国内的商业片
Director, please sign this for me.
导演请您给我签个名吧
How do you feel about your film winning the award?
您的影片获得大奖您对此有何感想
I feel a lot,
我的感触很多
you will read about it in my article.
你们将来在我的文章里是会看到的
Can I ask you questions other than your film?
问您影片以外的问题可以吗
I'm happy to answer as long as it's related to the film.
只要与影片有关我都乐意回答
You said that the actress and the sound recordist
您刚才说女主角和录音师
are in the hospital. What happened?
都住在医院里到底发生了什么事情
It's complicated. You will find out in the future.
一言难尽啊将来你们会知道的
Director Zheng, will your film be on abroad?
郑导演您拍这部片子在国外能有观众吗
I think it will be.
我想是会有的
Although our cultures and histories are different.
尽管我们的文化不同历史不同
The common love of mankind is always the same, right?
但是人类共同的爱总是相通的吧
You made lots of exploration in this film.
您在这部影片中作了很多探索
Do you think it's a success?
您认为是成功的吗
Well, it's hard to say. Let the critics comment on it.
这个太难讲了让评论界去评论吧
Director! Hope to seeing you again.
导演 欢迎您再来
Please accept our congratulations, director.
请接受我们的祝贺
Thank you very much!
非常感谢
Please stay, Goodbye.
好留步 再见
- Thank you. - Goodbye!
谢谢
- Goodbye. - Congratulations.
祝你再度成功
Thank you! Thank you very much!
多谢大家 谢谢大家啦
Hanged like this.
就吊死了
Time for medicine.
吃药了